Hello.

I'm Anton Medvedev.

I'm a software engineer and team lead with over 7 years of experience. I have hands-on experience designing and building distributed backends, data collection pipelines and multi-tenant applications. Technical proficiencies include both frontend and backend as well as software architecture and system design.

<u>anton@medv.io</u> <u>github.com/antonmedv</u> linkedin.com/in/anton-medv

Experience

Mar 2015 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

Aviasales / Jetradar

Currently backend developer on Aviasales core technology – search flights engine.

- Participated in refactoring legacy Python engine to Go that reduced the CPU usage by 30%.
- Designed and implemented a new embedded programming language for business rules engine.

Before frontend developer on Aviasales frontend team.

- Worked on refactoring legacy frontend application to React and TypeScript.
- Designed and implemented JavaScript template engine.

Before full-stack developer on Jetradar online travel agency.

- Development of the next generation of Jetradar OTA booking engine.
- · Maintained and improved Nginx configs settings management.

Aug 2014 - Mar 2015

Software Engineer

UMI.ru

Development of multi-tenant e-commerce platform based on umi-cms application.

- Designed and implemented SMS delivery system.
- Participated in development of cloud version of umi-cms.

Oct 2012 - Aug 2014

System Administrator

Vitim-Metal

Maintenance and development of custom CRM application.

Oct 2011 - Aug 2011

Web Developer

DeeepMe

Entertainment portal startup. Development of frontend and backend on PHP.

Education

2012 - 2014

St Petersburg University

Master's Degree in Computer Science

2005 - 2010

St. Petersburg State Marine Technical University

Specialist Degree in Applied Mathematics

Skills

Backend

- Go
- Python
- PHP
- Node.js
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- PostgreSQL
- AWS

Tools

- Linux
- Sketch

Frontend

- JavaScript
- React
- Redux
- GraphQL
- HTML/CSS
- UX Design

Other skills

- System design
- Applied Mathematics